<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Give Away</string>
    <string name="learn">In this modern development era , we as humans create a lot of waste and there are various problems with waste.
At the same time , there are many people round the earth,  who suffer to get a proper meal once in a day and
work so hard. We are here to create an interface that can connect you to the needy which helps you donate materials
that can reduce the production of waste.\n\n
    Education://Insights on waste management\n
Waste:\n
Waste are unwanted or unusable materials.\n
Waste is any substance which is discarded after primary use,or its worthless,defective of no use.
There can be two types of wastes, biodegradable(harmless substances) and non - bio degradable.
We either burry or burn the waste.
Consequences of waste disposal:
Disposing of waste has huge environment impacts and can cause serious problems.Some wastes will eventually rot,
but not all,and in the process it may smell, or generate methane gas, which is explosive and contributes to green house
effect.Thus this results in a lot of pollutions like air,water.
Waste management:
According to wiki:These are the activities and actions required to manage waste from its inception to its final disposal.
This includes the collection ,transport,treatment and disposal of waste.
Explaining in simple terms:
Waste management is a set of steps to manage the waste so that it doesnt give raise to any kind of serious problems
to life on earth.
From our childhood we have been learning three words-REDUCE REUSE and RECYCLE
These are the basic techninques of waste management.
Waste management is done on the already created waste.So instead of creating waste it would be a better option to
reduce the production of waste or reusing the materials which go to disposal instead of treating the disposed waste.
The most effective way to reduce the waste is to not create it in the first place.
WASTE DISPOSAL METHODS:\n\n


        The 3R rule or waste disposal:
Reduce:With individual efforts, we can reduce the waste we produce in the first place.For exaple—buying something
which is really necessary.
Reuse:We can use things again and again for different purposes.The cans brought at the super market can be reused
to fill loose items or plant a sapling.
Recycle:We can reform glass,plastic, metal and paper objects and convert them into useful substances.
There are various number of industries which recylce things such as paper industry produces new papers with old ones.
Broken or discarded plastic items can be melted and remoulded to form other useful substances.
  Incineration:
Incineration is a process of combusting wates , to transfrom them into base components,with the generated heat
being trapped for deriving energy.Pollution is caused by varied degrees dependent on nature of waste combusted
and incinerator design. Use of filters can check the pollution. The waste volume gets reduced by about 90 %.
Hazardous and toxic wastes can be easily be rid of by using this method.
  composting
it involves decompostion of organic wastes by microbes\n\n\n

      composting
it involves decomposition of organic wastes by microbes by allowing the waste to
stay accumulated in a pit for a long period of time. The nutrient rich compost can be used as plant manure.
However, the process is slow and consumes a significant amount of land. Biological reprocessing tremendously
 improves the fertility of the soil.\n\n\n

   Sanitary Landfill: This involves the dumping of wastes into a landfill.
 The base is prepared of a protective lining, which serves as a barrier between wastes and ground water,
 and prevents the separation of toxic chemicals into the water zone.
Waste layers are subjected to compaction and subsequently coated with an earth layer.
Soil that is non-porous is preferred to mitigate the vulnerability of accidental leakage of toxic chemicals.
Landfills should be created in places with low groundwater level and far from sources of flooding.
However, a sufficient number of skilled manpower is required to maintain sanitary landfills.\n\n

  Disposal in ocean/sea: Wastes generally of radioactive nature are dumped in the oceans far from active human
habitats. However, environmentalists are challenging this method,
as such an action is believed to spell doom for aquatic life by depriving the ocean waters of its inherent nutrients.</string>
    <string-array name="types">
        <item> </item>
        <item>Food</item>
        <item>Electrical</item>
        <item>Material</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
</resources>
